Chance Payne

Sparks, Nevada, United States

cmpayne5@gmail.com □ (916) 496-4863 ☐ in/chance-payne/

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with knowledge of a wide range a wide range of platforms, languages, and technologies. Constantly learning new technologies and will do what it takes to get the job done. Currently specializing in Android Development with past professional experience in Full Stack Web Design. Quick learner, currently picking up skills in iOS development and React.

SKILLS

Android Development: Java, Kotlin, SQL

Web Development: Javascript, HTML, Node.js, Angular, Java (Spring), Kotlin (yay cross compilation!)

EXPERIENCE

Lead Android Instructor

Lambda School

Remote, May 2018 - November 2019

- · Independently designed, built, and taught a 4 month Android Instruction program that encompassed 40 aspiring developers
- · Designed and wrote over **100 apps** for demo projects and evaluation challenges
- · Coordinated student competence evaluations through 3rd party with positive feedback, showing a high pass rate
- ·Onboarded and trained additional instructors and curriculum developers to convert material from Java to Kotlin

Software Engineer

VPI Technology Group

Draper, UT, June 2014 - June 2018

- · Developed multiple **Android** apps to communicate and control external devices over **Bluetooth**
- · Updated and maintain **Android** apps to control hardware devices over **Wi-Fi** and **USB** serial interfaces
- · Created C#, Node.js, and Python applications to control devices over different types of hardware interfaces
- · Designed **User Interfaces** for various projects

Owner/Operator

Business Printing Solutions

Folsom, CA, November 2010 - November 2012

- · Worked closely with clients to **design** a product to meet their specific needs
- · Designed and print marketing and internal documents using Adobe Creative Suite

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Utah Valley University

Orem, UT, January 2014 - May 2017

Course Highlights

Advanced Web Programming · Node.js, Angular, JQuery, Bootstrap, React

Built a variety of projects illustrating the strengths and weaknesses of different technologies

$\textbf{Principles and Patterns of Software Design} \cdot \textbf{Software Architecture and Design}$

Learned and used multiple Gang of Four design patterns

PROJECTS

Radiological Detection System · User Interface

Designed and built UI and assets for Multimillion-Dollar Radiation Detection System for the US Armed Forces

Smart Sprinkler System · Node.js, Angular, SQL

Built a server to connect to test devices being manufactured, allow for remote monitoring, and store test results for analysis

Wireless Projector App · Android, Java, iOS

Took over an app to connect to a web server running on mini projector. Focused on improving UI and user experience.

Bluetooth Android Apps · Android, Bluetooth, Java

Worked on apps to interact with devices over bluetooth including an Alarm Clock, Power Tools, a Smart Battery, and a Smart Lock

VOLUNTEER WORK

Boy Scouts of America

Cub Scout Den Leader, Venture Scout Leader · October 2017 – Current

- ·Run den meetings for a group of boys teaching them skills related to outdoors, education, and growing up
- · Help older (16+) young men plan and execute activities to learn about people and the world around them and prepare them foradulthood